《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
我的未婚妻死于前线的战斗
My fiancé died fighting on the front lines.
我看到艾丽克斯差点死掉
I saw Alex almost die.
把坠子给我
Give me the medallion.
你能翻译这些标记吗
Can you translate these markings?
我从嘶吼那里得到了一些东西  一个名字
I got something from Rip Roar. A name.
利维坦
Leviathan.
我可以利用超女达成我的目的
I can use Supergirl to achieve my ends.
她相信我们彼此信任  这么做就更简单了
That is easier to do if she believes there is trust.
马拉法克回到幻影区了
Malefic's back in the Phantom Zone.
你喜欢这里  对吧
You like it here, don't you?
非常喜欢
I like it very much.
你今天不在状态  超女
You're off your game today, Supergirl.
你也是
I could say the same to you.
别这么心急
Not so fast.
我要做好准备
I need to be ready.
我们不知道利维坦什么时候会再来袭
We don't know when Leviathan will strike next.
我们甚至都不知道是什么
We don't even know what it is.
他们要找的是什么
And what are they after?
所有的这些未知让我感到焦虑
All these unknowns make me feel anxious.
而我感到焦虑的时候  我就想打东西
And when I feel anxious, I want to punch things.
我们面临过未知的危险
We've faced unknown dangers before.
这次感觉不一样
This feels different.
我有不好的预感
I have a bad feeling about it.
艾丽克斯让超查部加班调查利维坦
Well, Alex has the DEO working overtime on Leviathan.
你确定不是别的事困扰你吗
Are you sure something else isn't bothering you?
在我告诉莉娜我是超女前
Before I told Lena I was Supergirl,
我非常害怕她的反应
I was terrified how she would react.
我很怕我会毁了我们的友情
I was so afraid I was going to ruin the friendship.
我还是不愿意去想这件事
I still hate thinking about it.
看着威廉失去朋友
Watching William lose his friend
让我有点不是滋味
hit a little too close to home.
荣恩  荣恩
J'onn? J'onn?
你现在可以出来了
You can come out now.
把坠子给我
Give me the medallion.
不可能
I don't think so.
我有世界上最复杂的安全系统
I have the most intricate security system in the world.
我完全了解了利维坦
I know all about Leviathan.
没人能完全了解利维坦
No one knows all about Leviathan.
人们无法了解利维坦
Leviathan is unknowable.
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
你会的
You will be.
她走了
She's gone.
我已经重新启动了顶层公寓的安保系统
I've reactivated heightened penthouse security.
你总是对的  卢瑟女士
You were right as always, Ms. Luthor.
利维坦会不惜代价夺回坠子
Leviathan will attempt to retrieve the medallion at all costs.
你何必为了毫无价值的东西去惹他们呢
But why would you provoke them over something of no value?
坠子对我来说很有价值
It has value to me.
坠子对我母亲来说很特别
The medallion was special to my mother,
而利维坦想利用它
and the fact that Leviathan wants it makes it useful.
莱克斯推测超人把所有针对他的武器
Lex theorized that Superman kept every weapon
放在了一个特殊的地方  一个堡垒里
that was ever used against him in a special facility, a fortress.
虽然他一直没找到  我想莱克斯说得对
And although he never found it, I think Lex was right.
我认为无害计划
I think the perfect dispersal device
完美的散播器就藏在那里吃灰
for Project Non Nocere is hidden there, gathering dust.
而利维坦会帮我找到它
And Leviathan is gonna help me find it.
请别低估利维坦的危险
Please don't underestimate the danger of Leviathan.
你应该取消L公司在公园举办的活动
You should cancel the L-Corp event at the park.
他们会去找你的
They will come after you.
让他们来吧
Let them come.
超女会救我
Supergirl will save me.
超 女
第五季 第七集
究竟发生了什么
Tell us exactly what happened.
我跟你们说过了  我没事
I already told you, I'm fine.
艾丽克斯  你应该去追查利维坦
Alex, you should be tracking Leviathan.
是的  还有嘶吼  但布莱尼已经在查了
Yes, and Rip Roar, but Brainy's on that,
所以别转移话题了
so just stop deflecting.
我昏倒前  被困在马拉法克的另一个幻象里
Before I fell, I was seized by another vision of Malefic.
另一个  还发生过这种事吗
"Another"? You've had more of these?
昨天在精神攻击时  我感觉到了马拉法克
Yesterday. I felt Malefic during the psychic attack.
就像是我可以感觉到他就在我身边
It's as if I can sense him all around me.
但是怎么会  我们已经把他送去幻影区了
But how? We sent him to the Phantom Zone.
我只能想到这些闪回
All I can think is these flashes are...
也许是我愧疚的症状
maybe symptoms of my guilt.
我知道我们别无选择
I know we had no choice
但是把马拉法克送回幻影区
but to send Malefic back to the Phantom Zone, but...
他过于危险  不能把他控制在地球上
I mean, he's too dangerous to be contained here on Earth.
就算如此  我还是觉得
Even so, I can't help feeling
我又一次冤枉了我弟弟
I've wronged my brother again.
这是第三次
This is the third time
他在我手上被判监禁了
he's been sentenced to confinement by my hand.
不  你弟弟自己做了决定
No, your brother made his own decisions.
你不能因此责怪自己
You can't blame yourself for that.
但看来你正在经历某种创伤
But it seems like you're going through some sort of trauma.
也许凯莉可以帮你
Maybe Kelly can help.
她帮不了我
She can't provide the help I need.
我会以火星人的方式来解决
I'll deal with this the Martian way.
坠子在哪
Where's the medallion?
我
I...
我拿不回来
I couldn't retrieve it.
这只是一项简单的任务
It was a simple task.
对任何一个人来说都很简单  但...
It would have been simple with any other human, but...
她是卢瑟家的人
she is a Luthor.
你知道我保护这个星球多久了吗
Do you know how long that I've been safeguarding this planet?
从开天辟地到现在
Since the beginning.
从我们和小行星一样大的船
And since our ship, as big as an asteroid,
再到消灭了恐龙
wiped out the dinosaurs.
然后人类崛起
Then humanity rose...
成为这个星球的祸害
and became a scourge to this planet,
我们千百年来
and for eons we have kept
控制着人类的破坏行为  但现在
their destructive behavior at bay, but now...
他们正以前所未有的方式在破坏地球
They're ravaging the Earth like never before,
我授予了你为我们的事业
and I granted you the privilege
做贡献的特权  你却失败了
of serving our cause, and you failed.
是她的失败  罗摩·可汗
Is it her failure, Rama Khan?
还是你的失败
Or is it yours?
你可以走了  玛戈特
You can go, Margot.
我们现在不需要只来软的
Using a carrot instead of a stick is not what we need right now.
人们将其称为玻璃心一代
Well, they are known as the "Snowflake generation."
2010年后成年的一代
被认为适应能力差  无耐心
什么意思  他们的心易碎吗
So what does that mean, they melt?
当我没说
Never mind.
我和你目标一致
You and I both share the same goal...
都想要制止那些不尊重这个星球的人
of wanting to put a stop to people who disrespect this planet.
我是来帮忙的
I'm here to offer my help.
你能帮什么忙
How can you help?
世界在不断改变和进化
The world is shifting, evolving.
前所未有地快
Moving faster than it ever has.
我们必须保持领先
We have to remain ahead of the curve.
以前的方法已经不适用了
The old ways aren't working--
上升的海洋
Oh, the rising of oceans
汹涌的河流成为常态
and the raging of rivers will always work.
缓一缓这股冲劲吧  罗摩·可汗
Give the brute force a rest, Rama Khan.
我们来试试我的科技吧
Let's try my technology.
我们的长者把照顾这个星球的任务留给了我
Our elder left the caretaking of this planet to me...
是有原因的
for a reason.
想做成一件事就得亲力亲为
You want something done, you have to do it yourself.
感谢大家在这么美好的一天来到这里
Thank you all for coming on such a wonderful day.
是什么
What was that?
我一直很喜欢在这些小路上跑步
Running these trails has always been my favorite way
能清理思绪
to clear my mind.
-是什么  -你感觉到了吗
- What was that? - Did you feel that?
我非常重视
It means so much to me
L公司可以参与保护这些土地
that L-Corp can have a hand in preserving these grounds.
你手上有我的东西
You have something that belongs to me.
那是什么
What was that?
利维坦
Leviathan.
多亏了自拍文化
Thank God for selfie culture.
因为这一代人
Because of this generation's
什么事都要实时
constant need to livestream everything,
所以我们有了袭击你的人的清晰照片
we've got a clear image of your attacker.
我就知道我之前见过这个人
And I knew I had seen that face before.
你记得公元526年的安提俄克吗
Do you recall Antioch, 526 AD?
古叙利亚首都
当时有场地震
It was an earthquake.
那是现代历史上第八大自然灾害
It was the eighth-largest natural disaster in modern history.
没错  很高兴你能回来  莉娜
Precisely. It's good to have you back, Lena.
神话因他而诞生
A myth was born that this man was the cause.
当然  科学家坚称
Now, of course, scientists
自然灾害并非人为
insisted that the natural disasters were natural,
但意外的历史转折说明他们都错了
but, in an ironic twist of history, they were wrong...
而散布恐慌的人是对的
and the fearmongers were right.
几处可靠信息确认
Several reliable sources place
他出现在历史上多次犯罪现场
this man at the scene of the crime throughout history.
庞贝末日  1887年黄河洪灾  波拉旋风
Pompeii, the Yellow River flood of 1887, the Bhola Cyclone,
甚至还有诺亚时期的洪水
even as far back as Noah's flood,
这个御土师都在场
this Earth-Bender has been spotted.
等一下  你叫他"御土师"
Excuse me, did you say "Earth-Bender"?
不然该怎么形容他
How else would you describe him?
他  他就是能控制土地
He... He literally manipulates the earth.
等下  庞贝末日  诺亚时期的洪水
Wait, Pompeii? Noah's flood?
怎么  他有几千岁吗
I mean, what is he, thousands of years old?
没错  也就是说  他是外星人
Correct. Which means that he is an alien
可以长生不老
with powers of longevity
超出我们的想象
this civilization has never conceived of.
难怪人们觉得他是神话
No wonder people thought he was a myth.
搞了这么多破坏
With all this destruction,
他的存在仍然是个谜
his existence is still shrouded in mystery.
他竟然让人相信他根本不存在
He's managed to convince the world he doesn't exist.
似乎是的
It seems so.
"利维坦"在希伯来《圣经》中出现了六次
The word "Leviathan" occurs six times in the Hebrew Bible.
从来没有
Never once does it appear
在历史科学文献中出现过
in any historical scientific literature.
那我们要怎么
So how are we supposed to
打败一个身份隐秘  活了几千年
fight a highly secretive, thousand-year-old alien
能力又远超我们的外星人
with powers that we have no idea how to beat?
我认识一个人  跟外星人斗了一辈子
Well, I know one person who spent his life fighting aliens,
-真的和假想的都有  -你哥哥
- both real and imagined. - Your brother.
我知道他的小武器都在峰脑堡垒里
I know most of his minor weapons are in Fort Summit,
但他真正骇人的武器
but his truly horrendous ones,
都被超人毁了
they were all destroyed by Superman.
并非如此
That's not necessarily true.
莱克斯的很多武器都在孤独堡垒
A lot of Lex's weapons are in the Fortress of Solitude.
这  这堡垒是超人造的
Oh, it's... It's a place Superman created.
里面放的是能伤害我们的武器
We keep things there that can harm us.
那你去堡垒
Well, you just go to the Fortress,
我给你一张莱克斯的武器清单
and I'll give you a list of every weapon that Lex ever created.
你为什么不直接跟我去
Why don't you come with me?
我们不知道那里有些什么武器
I mean, there's no telling what weapons we'll encounter.
我和布莱尼待在这里
And then, Brainy and I will stay here,
继续寻找
and we'll continue our search
嘶吼和这位御土师
for Rip Roar and this Earth-Bender.
超女  记住  最强大
Supergirl, remember the strongest,
最有力的武器是知识
most potent weapon is knowledge.
把堡垒信息库里找到的东西都发给我
So send me whatever you can find from the Fortress database.
准备好上路了吗
You ready for a road trip?
你确定我跟去没问题吗
Are you sure me going is a good idea?
当然  怎么了
Of course. Why wouldn't it be?
不知道  让卢瑟家的人进孤独堡垒吗
I don't know. A Luthor in the Fortress of Solitude?
没事  不过你得穿件外套
It's gonna be great. But you're gonna need a jacket.
父亲
Father,
我非常迷茫
I haven't been this lost
杀了曼彻斯特·布莱克后就这样
since after I killed Manchester Black.
你那时来到了我身边
You came to me then.
你帮我找回了自己
You helped me find myself.
现在我需要你的帮助
I need your help now.
荣恩  儿子
J'onn, my son!
爸爸  见到你真好
Father. It's good to see you.
我  我很抱歉
I am... I am so sorry.
我现在意识到我的所作所为
I know now what I did.
不可原谅
It was unforgivable.
我从你的记忆里抹去马拉法克
When I wiped your mind of Malefic...
犯下了最深重的罪孽
I committed the greatest sin.
不  荣恩
No, J'onn.
是我没有做好
It was I who failed.
你只是减轻了爸爸的痛苦
All you did was ease your father's suffering.
是我让你为难了
I forced your hand.
责任都在我
I take full responsibility.
但你让我来不是为了这个  对吧
But that's not the reason I'm here, is it?
没错
Uh, no.
父亲  我需要你的建议
Father, I need your counsel.
马拉法克要伤害我的家人
Malefic came after my family,
历史又重演了
and history repeated itself.
为了保护他们  我只能把他送回幻影地带
To protect them, I had to send Mal back to the Phantom Zone.
我想忘记这一切
I have tried to move on,
但我总感觉他在附近
but it's like I can feel him nearby.
因为他就在附近
That's because he is nearby.
-什么  -你弟弟在这里
- What? - Your brother is here.
他在我的思想里吗
You mean here in my mind?
不是
No.
他就在城里
I mean, he's across town.
有发现吗
Anything?
我回到莉娜受袭击的场景
I went back to the scene of Lena's attack
收集了土壤样本
and collected samples of the soil.
我也扫描了御土师的地震波特征
I am also scanning for the Earth-Bender's seismic wave signature.
目前没有发现
Nothing so far.
是御土师吗
Earth-Bender?
是嘶吼  找到他了
It's Rip Roar. We found him.
他不动了
He's not moving.
他被打晕了吗
Did they take him out?
怎么
Why?
后退
Fall back.
你没事吧  有没有受伤
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
我没事
I am intact.
容易受伤的是你  你受伤了吗
You're the fragile human. Are you harmed?
应该没有
I don't think so...
但我很愤怒
but I am furious.
他们放出嘶吼这个鱼饵
They dangled Rip Roar,
知道我们会上钩  现在
knowing that we would take the bait, and now...
我们一无所获
we've got nothing.
并不
Not nothing.
还有嘶吼的盔甲
We still have Rip Roar's armor.
我们马上进行检验
We should start studying it immediately.
艾丽克斯
Alex.
-你没事吗  -没事
- Are you all right? - Yeah. I'm okay.
但你被划了一道大口子
Oh, but you have a nasty cut.
好了  完美无缺
There. Perfect as always.
丹弗斯局长
Director Danvers!
这...太美了
This is... breathtaking.
这是我们在地球上的氪星
It's our Krypton on Earth.
入侵者  入侵者
Intruder! Intruder!
怎么了
What's happening?
检测到卢瑟家族DNA
Luthor DNA detected.
启用L协议
L-Protocol engage.
"L协议"  别别别别
"L-Protocol"? No. No, no, no, no, no!
卢瑟  立即放下
Luthor, relinquish your Kryptonite ring
你的氪石戒指和物质传送门手表
and your transmatter portal watch immediately.
我没戴戒指和手表  我不是莱克斯
I don't have a ring or a watch. I'm not Lex!
马上交出武器
Hand over the weapons at once,
否则堡垒将在十秒内进行攻击
or the Fortress will take offensive action in ten seconds.
她没有带武器
She's unarmed.
-十  九  八  -我来解决
- Ten, nine, eight... - I'll fix this.
-七  六  五  -快点  快点
- ...seven, six, five... - Come on, come on.
四  三  二
...four, three, two...
L协议已终止
L-Protocol terminated.
抱歉  我不知道
Sorry. I had no idea
超人居然会用这种极端手段
Superman would take such extreme measures.
不算极端  要是莱克斯知道这地方
No, if Lex knew about this place,
他肯定会不顾一切闯进来
he would do anything or kill anyone to get in here, so...
你跟莱克斯不一样
Well, you are not Lex.
你跟超人也不一样
And you are not your cousin.
我们俩的关系
We're miles beyond those boys
跟这对死敌不一样
with their sticks and their stones.
没错
Yes, we are.
马拉法克在纳欣诺市  他需要你的帮助
Malefic is in National City, and he needs your help.
我的帮助
My help!
如果这是真的  我爱的人都有危险了
If what you say is true, then everyone I love is in danger.
你弟弟伤害不了他们
Your brother cannot harm them.
他是囚犯
He is a prisoner.
囚犯
A prisoner?
谁的囚犯
Of whom?
这就要你自己发现了
That you must discover on your own.
爸爸  你一定要帮我
Father, you have to help me.
我要怎么找到他
How can I find him?
你必须做出选择
You must make a choice.
将你弟弟永远驱逐
Banish your brother once and for all...
还是拯救他的灵魂
or save his soul.
然而  想联系到马拉法克
However, there is only one way
只有一个办法
to reach Malefic.
这个办法需要你
And it requires you to...
冒着被他夺去生命的风险
risk your own death by his hand.
凯莉
Kelly.
你怎么来了
What're you doing here?
布莱尼给尼娅发短信说你们遇到了爆炸
Brainy texted Nia that you were both involved in an explosion.
我就冲来了
So I rushed over.
没事的  你  你不需要...
Really, you have... You have nothing...
你不需要担心
You have nothing to worry about.
别这样  别这样  不要哭
No, no. No, don't do that. Don't cry.
你要是哭  我就会哭
Because if you cry, then I'm gonna cry,
你知道我很讨厌在工作的时候哭
and you know I really hate crying at work.
你应该打给我的
You should have called.
确实  对不起
I should have, I'm sorry.
下次我肯定打给你  我保证
And next time, I will. I promise.
好
Okay.
等等  你要干什么
Wait. What're you doing?
我得回去工作
I have to go back to work.
你刚才差点被炸飞
You were nearly just blown up,
而且有轻微脑震荡
and you have a mild concussion.
等完全恢复才能回去工作
You can't go back out there until you're 100 percent.
好
Okay.
我们马上就到中心数据库了
We're almost to the central database.
但愿堡垒不要再攻击我
Assuming the Fortress doesn't attack me again.
谢谢你刚才救我
Thank you for saving me back there.
你不该让自己陷入危险
I shouldn't have had to,
但现在千钧一发的救援
but it does seem like dangerous saves
似乎成了我们的常态
are sort of our thing now.
是啊
Yeah, it does.
当然  以前都是我救你
Of course, it used to be me being the one that's saving you.
想象一下  我以为我在保护一位
Imagine, I thought I was protecting my fragile,
脆弱的朋友
vulnerable friend.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
记不记得我们去卡兹尼亚那次  差点坠机
Remember when we went to Kaznia and the jet was crashing?
我为了救我们的命都急疯了
And I was frantic to try and save us,
很想先救我的朋友...
desperate to save my friend before myself...
可是我不知道我的朋友其实会飞
Little did I know that that friend could actually fly.
抱歉我让你经历了这些
I'm so sorry I put you through that.
不  我觉得很了不起
No, it was impressive
你总是在我还没反应过来时救我
how often you saved me without me realizing...
你真是优秀的演员
I mean, you're an excellent actress.
告诉你真相之后我觉得很解脱
Telling you the truth was such a relief,
而且我好开心
and I'm so glad that now
现在我们可以坦诚相对  放下过去的一切
we can be honest with each other and all of that is behind us.
我也是
Me too.
这边请
It's this way.
你现在开心了吗
Are you happy now?
我搜索了全球  就是找不到他们
No. I've searched the globe. I can't find them.
你力量那么大  居然还是输了
With all your power, you were defeated,
坠子也没找到  甚至还跟丢了
you still don't have the medallion, and you lost them?
我会解决的
I will fix this.
罗摩·可汗  我们是盟友
Rama Khan, we're on the same side.
让我帮你吧
Let me help you.
你的力量多年来维持着情况稳定
Your power has kept things in alignment for ages,
但时代已经变了
but the world has changed.
人类现在被广大的网络连接着
Humans are connected by vast networks,
信息以光速在全球范围内传递
information flows across the globe at the speed of light.
我的技术就是我们需要的工具
My technology is a tool we need.
你没有办法找到她们
The way to reach them is beyond you.
我确实碰不到她们
They are beyond me.
但如果我在地球上
But if I can't feel the presence
感觉不到超女和卢瑟家女儿的存在
of Supergirl or the Luthor girl on Earth,
这就意味着
then that means...
他们在地球的某个地方
they're in the one place on Earth...
但那里没有土地
that is not of Earth.
那是多相式量子处理器吗
Is that a polyphasic quantum processor?
理论上已经讨论过很久
They've long been theorized,
但我第一次知道这东西真实存在
but I had no idea one actually existed.
我认为是的
I think it is.
我叫卡拉·佐·艾尔
My name is Kara Zor-El.
我想查询懂得御土术的古老外星人
I seek information on ancient Earth-bending aliens.
唯一符合描述的外星人
The only alien matching that description
来自氪星的姐妹星球  扎汉普星
comes from a sister planet of Krypton, Jarhanpur.
由于多年内战  该星球被毁
The planet was destroyed after years of civil wars,
但是五名领导者逃走了
but five of its leaders fled.
其中一位有着强大的能力
One of those leaders has the extraordinary power
能够控制土地
to bend the earth to his will.
该怎么阻止他
How do we stop him?
堡垒的军械库里有武器
There are weapons in the Fortress armory
能够伤到他
that can wound him.
那是用来虚弱氪星人的武器
Weapons thought to weaken Kryptonians.
是被莱克斯·卢瑟创造的
Those created by Lex Luthor,
也就是莉娜·卢瑟的哥哥
brother of Lena Luthor.
好了  这些信息够了
Thank you, that's all we need.
我们得赶紧去军械库
Well, we better get to the armory.
如果这样的外星人还有更多
If there are more of these aliens,
我们需要很大的一把枪
we're gonna need a really big gun.
我们应该提醒布莱尼
We should warn Brainy.
-好  -你介意我来吗
- Yeah. - Do you mind if I do it?
我从没用过量子处理器
I've never interfaced with a quantum processor before.
应该挺刺激的
It'd be a bit of a thrill.
请便
Knock yourself out.
搞定
Done.
走吧
Let's go.
唯一能够解救你哥哥的办法
The only chance of saving your brother...
就是完全卸下你的心防
is to let down your psychic shield entirely.
将你的脑海完全向他展开
Open your mind to him like a flower.
暴露一切
Complete vulnerability.
让他能够看到你的记忆
Allow him access to your memories
你最深处的想法  他能看到你的真相
and innermost thoughts, so he can see your truth.
如果我与马拉法克连接
If I bond with Malefic...
他可以选择毒害我的思想
he can choose to poison my mind.
我明知他很有可能直接杀了我
How can I make that choice knowing that he will
还有一切我爱的人
most likely murder me...
我怎么能做出这种选择
and kill everyone I love?
那就收回幻影地带投射器
Then retrieve the Phantom Zone projector,
让他回到虚空
send him back to isolation.
再惩罚他一次吗
And punish him again?
抱歉  儿子
I'm sorry, my son.
我的一生中  遇到了这个考验
In my lifetime, I faced this test.
我是否应该试图去联系他呢
Should I attempt to reach Malefic
这会有相当大的风险
and risk the utter decimation
让我的族人  家人  和我自己
of my people, my family, and myself
被他的能力毁掉
by his destructive power?
或是应该把他关起来
Or should I lock him away
这样他就不会伤害别人
where he cannot harm others?
我做了不可能的选择
I made my impossible choice.
本没有是非黑白
There is no such thing as right or wrong.
只有内心的安宁
There is only peace in one's heart,
而我从未找到过
something I never found.
父债子偿
The sins of the father are visited on the son.
你必须自己做出选择  荣恩
You must make your own choice, J'onn.
然后让赫隆米尔带你去见你哥哥
Then ask H'ronmeer to guide you to your brother.
无论你做出什么决定
No matter what you decide,
我都会爱你
I will love you for it.
就像我之前一直爱你和马拉法克
Just as I loved both you and Malefic...
很久很久
long ago.
这把枪好小
This gun is so tiny.
对  莱克斯当初这样设计是为了放进假发里
Yeah, Lex designed that to fit under his many human hair wigs.
所以是的
So, yeah.
电脑说我们应该找一些
Right, so the computer said we need to look for something
能伤到氪星人的武器
that will hurt Kryptonians.
看起来似乎很多
Seems to be a lot of that in here.
这是什么
What's this?
这是大清洗
That is Myriad.
我的家人创造的
My... My family created it.
大清洗来临的时候  我好像还在大都会
I think I was still in Metropolis when Myriad hit.
不过新闻上的影像资料看起来很可怕
The news footage, though, it was pretty horrific.
而现实甚至更加可怕
And reality was even worse.
我姨妈阿斯特拉和她丈夫  在不到一秒内
My Aunt Astra and her husband turned all of humanity
就让人类全部变成没有思想的僵尸
into mindless zombies in less than a second.
如果这屋内的武器我只能毁掉一个
If there is one weapon in this room I could destroy,
我会毁掉那个
it would be that one.
好  这个可能就是我们要的
Oh, well, this could be the ticket.
是声波泡
It's a sonic cannon.
它能朝目标发射出高频率的
It sends concentrated blasts of high-frequency ultrasonic waves
超声波束
at whatever you aim it at.
再做些小的调整
With a few slight adjustments,
我们或许可以用它让罗摩·可汗变虚弱
we can maybe use it to destabilize Rama Khan.
至少能争取足够的时间
I mean, at least long enough
来给他铐上能力抑制手铐
to put the power-dampening cuffs on him.
这是设计用来作恶的
It was designed for evil,
但或许我们可以用它来做些好事
but perhaps we can use it for some good.
证据证明普索尼人影响了匝尼安人的
...evidence that the Psions affected the Czarnians'
进化进程
evolutionary process.
十分明显
It's obvious.
氢分子与塔纳安原子一致...
Hydrogen molecules synonymous with Thanagarian atoms...
我的天啊  一切都这么清晰
Good God, it... It's just... It's clear!
我的抑制器
My inhibitor.
当然了
Of course.
抑制程度减弱了
I'm less inhibited.
简直太棒了
It's spectacular,
棒极了
truly and absolutely.
我的天啊
Great Scott!
当然  星期二  羊角面包  普拉提
Of course! Tuesday, croissant... Pilates...
意思是...
meaning...
利维坦的总部在纳欣诺市
Leviathan headquarters are in National City.
我知道我说过想要回去工作
You know, I know I said that I really wanted to get back to work,
但这样可比工作强多了
but this is so much better.
我真的
Look, I really...
很感谢你能来照顾我
appreciate being taken care of.
我习惯了自己承担一切
I'm so used to doing all this by myself.
但是有了你  这...
But being with you, it...
让我有回家的感觉
It feels like home.
怎么了
What's wrong?
当尼娅发信息告诉我你受伤时
When Nia texted me that you were hurt...
我心里一沉
my stomach dropped...
然后我看你有没有发信息给我  结果什么都没有
and I checked my phone for a text, and there was nothing there,
所以我设想了最糟糕的情况
so I assumed the worst.
因为我经历过最糟糕的情况
Because I've been through the worst,
这也不是我第一次这么害怕
and this isn't the first time that I've been terrified.
上周  我以为我会失去你
Last week, I thought that I was gonna lose you.
然后你送了我那顶头盔
But then you got me that helmet,
而你那么完美  那么兴奋
and you were so wonderful and so excited.
所以我压抑了自己的恐惧
And so I pushed past my fears,
我说服自己可以撑下去
and I convinced myself that I can handle it all.
但是我没有那么坚强
But I'm not that strong.
而我绝不会要求你去改变
And I would never ask you to change
或是要你去否决那个了不起
or ask you to deny the amazing
且勇敢的自我
and brave woman that you are.
凯莉  你在说什么
Kelly, what-- What are you saying?
我做不到
I can't.
利维坦
Leviathan.
我想我知道他们的位置了
I... I think I have their location.
我们必须马上出发
We must leave immediately.
去吧  快去吧
Go. Please, go.
就是这里吗
This is it?...
选择一栋不引人瞩目的建筑
Choosing an unobtrusive structure
是利维坦隐瞒他们基地位置的办法
is how Leviathan keeps their base a secret.
但却瞒不住我
Except from me.
我必须告诉你在爆炸之后
I must tell you that in the wake of the explosion,
我思维的可视范围似乎拓展了
it is as if the peripheral vision of my mind has expanded.
我现在每只隐喻性的眼睛都能看清六米之外的东西
I can now see 20/20 out of the corner of each metaphorical eye.
所以我在检查嘶吼的科技时才能看到
Which is how I saw, when examining Rip Roar's tech,
他头饰上的一些特殊痕迹
some peculiar markings on his headpiece.
当整个组合起来  便形成了一个标记
When joined together, it formed a symbol
在历史上出现过无数次
that can be seen countless times throughout history.
这个标记在危机和大灾难
A symbol that has been seen at disasters and catastrophes,
所有大毁灭事件中会出现
events of mass destruction.
这个标记将罗摩·可汗与利维坦联系在一起
A symbol that has connected Rama Khan and Leviathan,
还有  每个周二在做普拉提之前
but also... every Tuesday before Pilates,
我会来一杯早茶和羊角面包
I get a morning tea and croissant
就在这栋建筑后边的一家法式蛋糕店
at a delightful patisserie right past this building.
好吧  但愿你是对的
Okay, let's just hope that you are right.
听着  这是个寻找实据的任务
I mean, look. This is a fact-finding mission,
所以你得  冷静点
so please just... be cool.
我很冷静
I am cool.
你看  我选择这家咖啡店
You see, I chose this coffee shop
是因为这里距离
because of its close proximity
纳欣诺市的古代沥青坑最近
to National City's ancient tar pits,
那里具有重要的历史意义
a site of great importance in history,
并且也是可怕灾难的事发地
but also a site of terrible eruption.
你看  虽然散发着硫磺气味
You see, despite its sulfuric scent,
但它释放的能量增强了我的大脑功能
its emitted energy boosts my brain function.
而我相信利维坦选择这栋建筑
And I believe Leviathan has picked this building
也是出于同样原因
for the very same reason.
远古能量
The ancient energy.
看吧
Behold...
同样的标志出现在了这栋建筑的柱子上
The same symbol appears on this building's cornerstone.
很令人钦佩
It's impressive.
不仅是令人钦佩
Not just impressive.
是非常令人钦佩
Very impressive.
隐形装置
Cloaking tech.
要想除去这道屏障
In order to eliminate this barrier,
我们需要用与创造者近似的东西击打它
we'll have to hit it with something similar to the creator...
某种远古的东西
something ancient.
我知道了  来自于宏伟沥青坑的尘土
I've got it. The dust from the majestic tar pits
散发着绿星辐射
emits Veridian radiation,
重新分配能量  然后...
redistributing power, and...
别别别  先别按
No, no, no. Don't push it yet!
如果这部电梯通往的是你所设想的地方
If this elevator leads to where you think it's going,
我们会需要超女帮忙
we're gonna need Supergirl.
超女  我们找到了利维坦的位置
Supergirl, we've located Leviathan.
很好  把坐标发给我们  我们去找你
Great. Send us the coordinates and we'll come to you.
好  我去让超查部尽快开始进行宽频扫描
Okay, and I'll have the DEO start a broadband scan ASAP.
该走了
Time to go.
那是...
Is that...
没错
It is.
待在这里  把枪准备好
Stay here. Get the gun ready.
你觉得你能在我眼皮底下把她藏起来吗
You thought you could hide her from me?
我是古人  我是土地
I am ancient. I am the earth.
你是什么
What are you?
我  我只是生气你没敲门
Me? I'm just peeved you didn't knock.
我不明白  一切证据都指向这里
I don't understand. Every piece of evidence led here.
至少我们知道我的安全措施起作用了
At least we know my security measures are working.
咱们走吧
Let's get out of here.
我说了  我就是土地
I told you, I am the earth!
"土地"  但这座堡垒不是土壤建成的
"The earth." But the Fortress isn't made of earth.
我很好奇  你是怎么找到我们的
I'm curious, how did you find us?
我搜遍全球找不到你
When I searched the globe and couldn't find you,
所以我去了我所知道你唯一能够躲藏的地方
I went to the one place that I knew that you could hide.
我想你漏了点什么
I think you overlooked something.
你在我家里
You're in my house.
我有主场优势
I have home court advantage.
欢迎来到氪星  老家伙
Welcome to Krypton, old man.
忘记我了吗
Forget about me?
你下次不会再逃出我的掌心了  氪星人
You won't survive me again, Kryptonian.
莉娜
Lena?
Lena.
你手上为什么会有"大清洗"
Why do you have Myriad?
你逮到我了
Well, you caught me.
我有大清洗是因为我利用了你
I have Myriad because I'm using you...
就像你利用了我一样
like you used me.
我从没利用过你
I never used you.
你记得你最终告诉我你是超女的时候吗
Do you remember when you finally told me you were Supergirl?
你哭了
You were weeping.
大鳄鱼的眼泪
Big crocodile tears.
而我的眼泪是真心的
Well, I wept real tears,
在那之前几周为你而流的伤心泪
bitter tears over you weeks before.
什么  我以为...
What? I... I thought...
你知道多久了
How long had you known?
我是在杀死我哥哥那天知道的
I found out the day I killed my brother.
莉娜  你没有杀死莱克斯  是我杀的
Lena, you didn't kill Lex, that was me.
我看着他
I... I watched him...
我看到他跌落
I saw him fall.
你看到他跌落  但你看到他落地了吗
You saw him fall, but did you see him land?
你看到他死了吗
Did you see him die?
我看到了  让我告诉你  那场景很美
I did, and let me tell you, it wasn't pretty.
那不可能
That's impossible.
身为卢瑟家的人  什么都有可能
Anything's possible when you're a Luthor.
莱克斯用了他的物质传送门手表
Lex used his transmatter portal watch.
我知道他会去哪里
I knew exactly where he'd go.
去我们小时候最爱的那座小屋
To the cabin we loved when we were children,
所以我在那里等他
so I was there waiting for him.
我的枪都上好膛了
I had the gun ready... loaded.
我能感受到枪在我手上的重量
I could feel the weight of it in my hands.
我的每一根神经都在抗拒  但是
Every fiber in my being rebelled, but I--
我不想杀他  但我知道我必须这样做
I didn't want to do it, but I knew I had to
因为如果莱克斯活着  这个世界就不安全
because if Lex lived, the world wouldn't be safe,
我的朋友们就不安全
my friends wouldn't be safe.
所以我逼自己开枪
So I forced myself to pull the trigger.
我一枪打在了我亲哥哥的胸口上
I shot my own brother in the chest.
他在临终时说
His final words to me were...
我是个傻瓜
that I was a fool,
我最好的朋友  我所有的朋友都在骗我
that my best friend, that every friend I had was lying to me.
他临终前告诉我你就是超女
With his dying breath, he told me that you were Supergirl.
莉娜  你要相信我
Lena, you have to believe me,
我从没想过羞辱你
I never meant to humiliate you.
不  在我来到这座城市时
No. When I came to this city,
我向自己保证再也不会相信任何人  然后
I promised myself that I would never trust anyone again, and...
我就遇见了你
then I met you.
你用你的热情
You chipped away at my
和诚挚粉碎了我的盔甲
armor with your warmth and your earnestness,
你让我重新相信人类和友谊
and you convinced me to trust in people and friendship again,
我不顾自己的判断  相信了你
and against my better judgment, I did,
我一直在告诉你我的致命要害
all the while telling you about my Achilles heel...
就是背叛
betrayal.
我向你倾诉
I confided in you
我过去认识的每个人都背叛了我
that everyone in my past had betrayed me.
当你爱的人
About how much it hurt...
对你撒谎  背叛你
to have someone you love
是多么的痛苦
lie to you and betray you.
我一遍又一遍地告诉你
I spelled it out to you over and over again,
求你不要辜负我的信任
essentially begging you not to violate my trust,
求你不要再一次证明我是个傻瓜
begging you not to prove that, once again, I was a fool.
你不断地向我保证
You reassured me ad nauseam
你永远不会骗我
that you would never lie to me,
你永远不会伤害我
that you'd never hurt me.
然而一直以来  在我们的友谊中
And all the while, there wasn't a single
都没有一个诚实的时刻
honest momet in our friendship--
不不  那不是真的
No! No, that is not true--
不  我为你  为我们的朋友杀了我哥哥
No! I killed my brother for you, for our friends!
难道你不明白你做了什么吗
Don't you understand what you've done?
在你发现我的身份时  为什么不马上来找我
When you found out, why didn't you come... to me right away,
让我来解释...
so I could explain--
"解释"吗
"Explain"? Yeah?
如果你那么恨我  为什么
If you hate me so much, why...
为什么不在普利策奖典礼上揭发我
Why not out me at the Pulitzer party?
为什么这么久还假装是我的朋友
Why pretend to still be my friend this long?
因为我想以其人之道还治其人之身
Because I wanted you to experience what you did to me.
体会我的感受
Feel what I felt.
我理解你的痛苦和愤怒
I understand your pain and your fury and...
你是对的
And you're right.
我犯了个大错
I made a big mistake,
或许是我人生中最大的错误  但是求你
maybe the biggest mistake of my life, but please...
莉娜  请不要将大清洗带离堡垒
Lena, please don't leave the Fortress with Myriad.
请不要因为我的错误而做坏事
Please don't let my mistake push you to do something terrible.
-你是个好人  -不
- You are a good person. - No!
不  你再也没有资格评判我的品质
No, you don't ever get to tell me who or what I am again.
入侵者  入侵者
Intruder! Intruder!
你重新编辑了堡垒的防御系统来攻击我吗
Did you reprogram the Fortress defenses to attack me?
是的
Yes.
我把它和我手上的这个小按钮连接起来
And I rigged it to answer to this little button I have in my hand.
你想杀了我吗
Are you going to try to kill me?
不  超女  我不会杀你
No. Supergirl, I'm not gonna kill you.
我不是坏人
I'm not a villain.
你不该把我当成坏人对待
You shouldn't have treated me like one.
你是来收拾残局的吗
And now you've come to finish what you started?
是的
I have.
但我不会
But I will not...
把你送回幻影区了  弟弟
send you back to the Phantom Zone, brother.
我在那里度过了一生  哥哥
I spent lifetimes there, brother.
虚无的一生
Lifetimes of nothing.
没有空气  没有时间
No air, no time,
看不见  闻不到
no sight, no smell.
只有我的心
Nothing but my heart...
中止跳动
suspended mid-beat.
一次极度折磨  没有尽头的中止
An excruciating suspense that never stops.
屏住永不能呼出的一口气
A breath you can never exhale.
你建议我把你送到那里吗
Is that where you suggest I send you?
如果你愿意可以的
You can if you wish.
但是我把这个带来
But I bring this only now as an offering...
是为了让你知道
to show you
我来到这里  是真心想来...
that I mean it when I say that I have come here...
赎罪
to make amends.
骗子
Liar!
马拉
Mal,
我真希望在我们小的时候
I wish I could've broken
能把你从那个山洞里救出来
you out of that cave when we were children.
能有方法
Found some way to...
向你表明
show you that
你是我的弟弟  而且我爱你
you were my brother and I loved you!
你并不爱我
You didn't love me.
你为我感到羞耻
You were ashamed of me.
你把我藏了起来
You hid me away.
当我像个怪物一样
Banished me...
放逐了我
like a monster!
我们害怕你
We were afraid of you.
我们都害怕你
We were all afraid of you.
我害怕你
I was afraid of you.
我们大错特错了
And we were so wrong.
当我把你从我们的记忆中抹去时
I destroyed my honor...
我毁了我的荣誉
when I wiped you from our memories.
但是  马拉  我的所作所为是出于爱
But, Mal, what I did, I did for love.
现在我想起来了
Now that I remember...
我无法忍受这种痛苦
I cannot live with this pain.
所以  弟弟
And so, brother...
我甘愿
I beg your forgiveness
与你联结
by submitting myself...
请求你的原谅
to the Bond.
看看我的内心  弟弟
Look into my mind, brother.
就这么简单吗
It's that easy?
你把自己交给我
You hand yourself over to me.
我很乐意去看  哥哥
I will look... with pleasure, brother.
然后我会立马杀了你
Right before I kill you.
我愿意不惜一切
I'm willing to risk everything...
为了让你看到我的真相
in order for you to see my truth,
我的心  我的灵魂  我的内心
my heart, my soul, and my mind.
我看见了
I saw.
-我...  -不用说  我知道
- I was-- - No, it's... I know.
你熬过了
You have been through
一段难以忍受的经历
an unbearable experience.
你失去了你的未婚妻  我甚至无法
You lost your fiancee, and I can't even
想象以那种方式失去你爱的人
begin to imagine losing someone that you love...
是什么感觉
in that way.
你是如此的坚强
You're just so strong
让我没能意识到你仍在痛苦中
that I didn't... I didn't realize that you were still suffering,
很抱歉我没能更细心地觉察到这一点
and I'm really sorry that I wasn't more sensitive to that.
-不  别...  -你先  先
- No, don't-- - Just... Just...
听我说
Listen...
当你遇见我时
When you met me,
我失去了我的另一半
I was just half a person.
我自己的伤口还隐隐作痛
I was still hurting from my own wounds
而你  你帮助我愈合
and you... you helped me heal.
从伤口结成伤疤
You know, from wounds to scars,
再化作回忆
to just memories.
那也是我想为你做的
That's... That's all I want to do for you.
我想帮你愈合
Hey, I want to help you heal.
我想和你一起
I want to be with you
克服你的恐惧  一起面对
and face down your fears and do it together.
我想帮你愈合
I want to help you heal.
如果这是不可能的呢
And what if that's not possible?
我知道这有可能
Well, I know that it is.
你怎么知道
How?
因为你愈合了我
Because you healed me.
当我说你让我有家的感觉时  我是认真的
I meant it when I said that you feel like home.
你也让我有家的感觉
You feel like home, too.